<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Something in answer to a law lately made at the first sessions of the General Court held at Boston in New-England, May the 28th, 1679 : and published by their order, Edw. Rawson, Secretary : the title of the law, viz. Meeting-houses not to be erected without licence, &amp;c.</title>
            <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1679</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 11 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A40257</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1911</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R36421</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">15690298</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 15690298</idno>
            <idno type="VID">104394</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A40257)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 104394)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1593:1)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Something in answer to a law lately made at the first sessions of the General Court held at Boston in New-England, May the 28th, 1679 : and published by their order, Edw. Rawson, Secretary : the title of the law, viz. Meeting-houses not to be erected without licence, &amp;c.</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>20 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1679]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Signed on p. 18: The 19th of the 7th month, 1679. G.F.</note>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: stained.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Persecution.</term>
               <term>Freedom of religion.</term>
               <term>Society of Friends --  Apologetic works.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:104394:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>Something in ANSWER to a LAW Lately made at the firſt Seſſions of the General Court held at <hi>Boſton</hi> in New-England May the 28th, 1679. And publiſhed by their Order, <hi>Edw, Rawſon</hi> Secretary</head>
            <head type="sub">The Title of the LAW, <hi>viz. Meeting-Houſes not to be Erected with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Licence, &amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſwer.</hi> VVHat would the <hi>New-England</hi> Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernours and Prieſts have done to Chriſt and his Twelve and Seventy Diſciples, if they had been in their day?</p>
            <p>For doth not Chriſt ſay, (to encourage Meetings) <hi>Where Two or Three are gathered together in my Name<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  <pb n="2" facs="tcp:104394:2"/>I will be in the midſt of them;</hi> to exerciſe his Offices in the midſt of them, as he was a Prophet and a Prieſt, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>And did Chriſt or his Diſciples go to get Licence of the Free-men of every Town where they came to meet in? or did they go to the <hi>Jews</hi> for Licence to meet in ſuch and ſuch Houſes? or muſt they not meet except they had Licenced Houſes from the <hi>Jews,</hi> or <hi>Herod,</hi> or <hi>Pontius Pilate</hi> the Governour?</p>
            <p>Now you ſay, <hi>That the Scripture is your Rule;</hi> then what Scripture have you, that the true <hi>Chriſtians</hi> muſt not meet, and have Meeting Houſes on their own Ground, except they have a Licence from you? Have you not this from the <hi>Papiſts</hi> or <hi>Heathen?</hi> And would not you have pluck't down the Houſes and Places where Chriſt and his Diſciples met, or take away and ſell and demoliſh them, if you had been in their day? and do not you manifeſt your ſelves to be more like <hi>Jews</hi> and <hi>Heathens</hi> than <hi>Chriſtians?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now <hi>New England</hi>'s <hi>Presbyterians</hi> Law is as follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth.</p>
            <p>
               <q>FOraſmuch as it hath too often happened, that through Differences ariſing in ſeveral Towns, and on other Pretences, there have been Attempts by ſome Perſons to erect Meeting-Houſes, although on pretence of the Publick Worſhip of God on the Lord's Day, yet thereby laying a Foundation (if not for Schiſm and Sedition, for Error and Hereſie) for perpetuating Diviſions, and weakening ſuch Places where they dwell in the comfortable ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port of the Miniſtry, orderly ſettled amongſt them.
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:104394:2"/>For Prevention whereof for the future, it is order<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by this Court, and the Authority thereof, That no Perſon whatſoever, without the Conſent of the Free-men of the Town where they live, firſt or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derly had, and obtained at a publick Meeting aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled for that end, and Licence of the County Court, or in Defect of ſuch Conſent, and Licence by the ſpecial Order of the General Court, ſhall erect or make uſe of any Houſe, as aboveſaid: And in caſe any Perſon or Perſons ſhall be convicted of tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greſſing this Law, every ſuch Houſe or Houſes, wherein ſuch Perſons ſhall ſo meet more than Three Times, with the Land where ſuch Houſe or Houſes ſtand, and all private Wayes tending thereto, ſhall be Forfeited to the Uſe of the County, and diſpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed of by the County Treaſurer, by Sale or Demo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhing, as the Court that gave Judgment in the caſe ſhall order.</q>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> So hereby we underſtand, that none ſhall erect any Houſe to keep them from the Wind and Weather to Worſhip God in, without your Licence and Authority. But will your Court or Free-men grant any Licence in theſe things to the People of God in Scorn called <hi>Quakers,</hi> if they deſire it?</p>
            <p>And did ever Chriſt and his Diſciples or Apoſtles Take, Sell or Demoliſh Meeting-Houſes, and the Ground and High-wayes of any other People, that w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>re not of their Religion, becauſe they had not a Licence from them? Prove this by Scripture, who ſay, <hi>It is your Rule,</hi> and call your ſelves <hi>Chriſtians?</hi> Or hath the King of <hi>Old England</hi> given you any ſuch
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:104394:3"/>Authority in your Patent to make Forfeiture and Sale of, and to Demoliſh the Meeting-Houſes, Lands and High-wayes of God's People, that they have e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected to Worſhip him in? We do not believe that your Patent will juſtifie you in this thing; but contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry to it is your Practice, and contrary to the Scriptures of the New Teſtament alſo.</p>
            <p>But as <hi>Solomon</hi> ſaith, <hi>When the Righteous are in Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority, the People Rejoyce; but when the Wicked bear Rule, the Righteous Mourn,</hi> Prov. 29.2.</p>
            <p>But are not you in the ſteps of the <hi>Gentiles,</hi> with your Authority? Read <hi>Mat.</hi> 20.25. and <hi>Luke</hi> 22.25.</p>
            <p>And did not the Elders, and the Chief Prieſts, and the Great Profeſſing <hi>Jews,</hi> ask Chriſt, <hi>By What Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority he did thoſe things?</hi> and <hi>Who gave him that Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority?</hi> ſhewing that he had not that Authority from them. And did not he and his Diſciples often meet together? <hi>Mat.</hi> 21.24. &amp; <hi>Mark</hi> 11.28.</p>
            <p>And in <hi>Luke</hi> 20. The Chief Prieſts, and Scribes, and the Elders came unto Jeſus, when he was preach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Goſpel and teaching the People, ſaying, <hi>Tell us by what Authority thou doſt theſe things: or Who is he that gave thee this Authority?</hi> And Chriſt asked them, <hi>Whether the Baptiſm of</hi> John <hi>was from Heaven, or of Men?</hi> And they reaſoned with themſelves, ſaying, <hi>If we ſhall ſay, from Heaven, he will ſay, Why then believed you him not? And if we ſay of Men, all people will ſtone us;</hi> for they did believe that <hi>John</hi> was a Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phet; and ſo they anſwered, <hi>They could not tell:</hi> And ſo it ſeems the Chief Prieſts, and Scribes, and Elders did not believe in <hi>John</hi>'s Teſtimony for Chriſt, though many others did.</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:104394:3"/>
            <p>And alſo, did not then the Chief Prieſts ſend Scribs to watch Chriſt, to take hold of his words, that ſo they might deliver him to the Power and Authority of the Governour?</p>
            <p>And had not <hi>Saul</hi> Authority from the Chief Prieſts, to bind all that called on the Name of Jeſus? and did not he breath out Threatnings and Slaughter againſt the Diſciples of Chriſt Jeſus, and went to the High Prieſts, and deſired of them Letters to go to <hi>Damaſcus</hi> to the Synagogues, that if he found any of this Way, whether Men or Women, he might bring them bound to <hi>Jeruſalem?</hi> And have not you gone on with your Authority in the Way of <hi>Saul,</hi> breathing out your Threatnings and Slaughtering the Diſciples of Chriſt, and bringing them bound to your Courts at <hi>Boſton,</hi> inſtead of <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> and Priſoned and Hanged them on your Gallows? But is not your Authority and Commiſſion larger than <hi>Saul</hi>'s? for though <hi>Saul</hi> brea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thed out Threaning and Slaughter againſt the true <hi>Chriſtians,</hi> yet we do not read that they gave him ſuch Authority, as to make Sale of, and Demoliſh their Meeting-places, and Land, and Wayes to them; read <hi>Acts</hi> 9, &amp; 26.</p>
            <p>And doth not <hi>Paul,</hi> when he was Converted, call this <hi>Madneſs</hi> in himſelf? then is it not the ſame in you, and not <hi>Soberneſs? Acts</hi> 26.</p>
            <p>And did not the Dragon give the Beaſt Power, and his Seat and great Authority? and did not he cauſe all, both Small and Great, to worſhip him; and them that would not worſhip the Image of the Beaſt, ſhould be Killed? And all did worſhip him, but thoſe whoſe Names were written in the Lamb's Book
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:104394:4"/>of Life, ſlain from the Foundation of the World, <hi>Revelat.</hi> 13.</p>
            <p>And ſo now try your ſelves, whether you are not like the Beaſt, and <hi>Jews,</hi> and <hi>Papiſts,</hi> and worſe than ſome of the <hi>Heathen Romans,</hi> who let <hi>Paul</hi> preach the Kingdom of God, and thoſe things that concerned the Lord Jeſus, in his own Hired Houſe, and no man forbidding him, and received all that came in unto him (to wit, his Hired Houſe.) So <hi>Paul</hi> had a Meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing-place in his Hired Houſe, for all that came unto him. But the <hi>New-England</hi> Prieſts and Governours, it ſeems, would have forbidden him, if they had been in that day; and not let <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> an Houſe to Hire, for <hi>Paul</hi> to preach Chriſt in; no more than you will now let the People of God called <hi>Quakers</hi> have Meeting-Houſes, and Wayes unto them.</p>
            <p>And was not the Church in <hi>Philemon</hi>'s Houſe? ſo was not his Houſe a Meeting-place? ſee in <hi>Philemon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And doth not <hi>Paul</hi> ſay in <hi>Col.</hi> 4.15. <hi>Salute the Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren which are in</hi> Laodicea, <hi>and</hi> Nymphos, <hi>and the Church which is in his Houſe?</hi> Had they not a Meeting-place then in his Houſe to worſhip God in?</p>
            <p>And <hi>Priſcilla</hi> and <hi>Aquilla</hi> the Church was in their Houſe, <hi>Rom.</hi> 16. and had they not there a Meeting-place then in <hi>Priſcilla</hi>'s Houſe to worſhip God in?</p>
            <p>And the Apoſtle <hi>Paul</hi> ſaith in 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 14. <hi>When the Church is met together in one Place.</hi> Now though the Church did meet together in one Place, or in a Houſe, yet the Church is built upon Chriſt the Rock, which the Gates of Hell cannot prevail againſt, as in <hi>Matth.</hi> 16.</p>
            <p>So it is not like for the <hi>New-England</hi> Magiſtrates
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:104394:4"/>and Prieſts for them to prevail againſt this Rock, nor the Church that is built upon it; neither can they ſell this High-way of Light and Righteouſneſs that leads to it.</p>
            <p>But what if the <hi>New-England</hi> Governours &amp; Prieſts had lived in the dayes of <hi>Philemon,</hi> and <hi>Priſcilla,</hi> and <hi>Aquilla,</hi> and the <hi>Romans,</hi> and the <hi>Corinthians,</hi> who kept the true primitive <hi>Chriſtian</hi> Meetings in their Houſes, would not the Horn of their Law have puſhed their Houſes down, and thrown them out, and have made Forfeiture and Sale of, and Demoliſhed the Houſes, Lands and High-wayes to them, and yet profeſſed themſelves <hi>Chriſtians,</hi> and the Scripture their Rule herein? Oh! that ever men ſhould make a Profeſſion of God, and Chriſt, and Chriſtianity, and yet Themſelves, who did flee in the time of Perſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion for the Liberty of their Conſciences, do perſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute others for their tender Conſciences, that cannot bow to their Image, that they have ſet up in the Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derneſs of <hi>America.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And as for the Differences ariſing in Towns, and on other Pretences, as you ſay, <hi>there have been Attempts by ſome Perſons to erect new Meeting-Houſes, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> Now have not your Governours, and Prieſts and Elders been the Cauſe of the Differences? and is not every one to be fully perſwaded in their own Hearts and Minds? For whatſoever is not of Faith, is Sin.</p>
            <p>And by what Law of <hi>Old England</hi> have you Power to take peoples Lands, High-wayes and Houſes from them, and make them Forfeit, Sell and Demoliſh them, if that you do own the Laws of <hi>England,</hi> which
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:104394:5"/>are to preſerve people in their Houſes, Lands and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perties. But your Laws will take them from people, and Sell and Demoliſh them, with their Lands &amp; High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes, becauſe people worſhip God in them really in Spirit and in Truth, which the Devil is out of; this is more than Pretence: And becauſe they cannot own nor joyn with you Perſecuting Rulers and Prieſts in your pretended Worſhips, no more than the three Children could joyn with <hi>Nebuchadnezzar</hi>'s. For if that perſecuting ſpirit in the Prieſts &amp; Rulers of <hi>New-England</hi> can worſhip God with it, that do Whip, and Hang, and Burn in the Hand, and Baniſh upon pain of Death, and Cut Off Ears, and Spoil the Goods of the Servants of Chriſt; and now to make Forfeiture and Sale of, and to Demoliſh their Meeting-Houſes, Lands and Wayes to them: If this perſecuting Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit be a Worſhipper of God, then <hi>Pharaoh,</hi> and <hi>Nebu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chadnezzar,</hi> and <hi>Herod,</hi> and the <hi>Beaſt</hi> and <hi>Whore</hi> were Worſhippers of God; and the <hi>Chief Prieſts</hi> and <hi>Jews</hi> that Crucified Chriſt, and <hi>Saul</hi> with his Authority and Licence from the High Prieſts to perſecute, were Worſhippers of God. But <hi>Paul</hi> will tell you, whilſt he did ſuch things, he was a Mad Man; and ſo your Madneſs hath been known herein, and not your Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration and Sobriety.</p>
            <p>And the Truth (which we have received, profeſs and practiſe) layes no Foundation for Error, nor Hereſie, nor Schiſm, nor Sedition, nor for Perpetua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting Diviſions, nor Weakening the Places where they dwell in the comfortable Support of the Miniſtry ſettled amongſt them (as you ſay.) For there is no other Foundation to be laid, but what is laid already
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:104394:5"/>(to wit, Chriſt Jeſus) who was the Foundation of the Prophets and Apoſtles: And all the Believers in the Light, as Chriſt commands, build upon him, the Foundation which the ſpirit of Schiſm, and Error, and Hereſie, and Seducing cannot build upon. But the preaching of Chriſt and his Goſpel diſquieted <hi>Diana</hi>'s Worſhippers, as now it does you. And the <hi>Jews</hi> Prieſts and Elders, Scribes and Phariſees were diſquieted; yea, the very Birth of Chriſt made ſuch an Uproar in <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> where was the higheſt out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Profeſſion and Worſhip in the World. And alſo <hi>Herod</hi> gathered the Wiſe Men and Prieſts toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, to know where Chriſt ſhould be born; and they ſaid, <hi>At Bethlehem;</hi> and then <hi>Herod</hi> ſlew the Young Children for his ſake.</p>
            <p>And did not you the <hi>Herods</hi> of <hi>New-England,</hi> Whip and Baniſh, and after HANG four Servants of Chriſt, when he was manifeſted in his people in <hi>New-England, Herod</hi>-like?</p>
            <p>And ſo, hath not the Forming of Chriſt in his People made the <hi>New-England</hi> Magiſtrates, and Prieſts and Profeſſors all of an Uproar; and that by your Law now, the people of God ſhall neither have Land nor Houſes to meet together to worſhip God in his Holy Spirit and Truth, who cannot live under your perſecuting murdering Prieſts ſpirit? For Chriſt ſaith, <hi>Such as deſtroy Mens Lives,</hi> though it be even their Lives who would not receive him, <hi>they do not know what Spirit they are of themſelves.</hi> And therefore, how can we truſt our Bodies, Souls and Spirits in the Hands of ſuch Uncomfortable Miſchie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vous Miniſters? For they preach War, and Bloodſhed,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:104394:6"/>and Perſecution; and that is not the <hi>Goſpel of Peace:</hi> And the Wars, and Strivings, and Fightings ariſe from your own Luſts, and not from the Truth, nor Goſpel of Peace. For would you think it well, if the King ſhould ſend over ſome Biſhops, &amp; ſet up his own Religion among you, which he judges is better than yours, and make a Law, that you muſt all come and hear the <hi>Common-Prayer;</hi> if not, you muſt he Hang'd on the Gallows, as you did the <hi>Quakers,</hi> and have your Ears cut, and branded with a Hot Iron, and have your Bodies (both of Men and Women) ſtript to the Waſte, and Whipt until your Bodies are made like a Jelly, and your Womens Paps cloven in the midſt with whipping, and your Goods ſpoiled, and Houſes taken from you and forfeited, and Land, and Houſes and Wayes all ſold, and given to the uſe of the Country? what would you ſay to this? Have not you ſerved the King's Subjects ſo, only for their Tenderneſs of Conſcience, you that pretend Liberty of Conſcience? And this was never the practice of true <hi>Chriſtians,</hi> nor the Apoſtles, nor Miniſters, nor Meſſengers of Chriſt Jeſus. And ſo the Strife is from that inwardly Ravening Spirit, like Wolves in Sheeps Clothing, and Luſt in your ſelves, from whence ari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes your War, who will not let peaceable People meet to worſhip God in Spirit and in Truth, as Chriſt hath commanded.</p>
            <p>For it is not the Work of you <hi>Herodian Caeſars</hi> to preſcribe God a Worſhip: For Chriſt hath ſet up a Worſhip above ſixteen hundred years ſince. But God be thanked, that your Beaſts Horn reaches no farther than <hi>New England;</hi> for if it did, it would ſoon pull down our Meeting Houſes in <hi>England,</hi> and
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:104394:6"/>other Meeting-Houſes alſo, that are contrary to you, in all the Kings Dominions, and make their Houſes forfeited, and ſell them, and the Land and Wayes too. And though you ſay the price of them muſt be given to the Country; but is it not very likely, that the Beaſt after he had puſhed them down with his Horn, would ſwallow down the price of all?</p>
            <p>And did not <hi>Ananias</hi> the High Prieſt tell <hi>Felix, That</hi> Paul <hi>was a Peſtilent Fellow, and a Mover of Sediti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on among all the</hi> Jews <hi>throughout all the World, and a Leader of the Sect of the</hi> Nazarenes, <hi>Acts</hi> 24.</p>
            <p>And ſo are not you found in the very ſame Lan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guage and Spirit, againſt the Life of Chriſtianity, and ſuch as walk in it.</p>
            <p>And did not the <hi>Jews</hi> ask <hi>Paul, What he thought of that Sect,</hi> to wit, of the <hi>Chriſtians?</hi> and they ſaid, <hi>They knew it was every where ſpoken againſt,</hi> Acts 28.</p>
            <p>And ſo we know, it is not only ſpoken againſt now (by you that are of the Birth of the Fleſh) but they are perſecuted that are born and led of the Spirit, and walk in Chriſt the New and Living Way.</p>
            <p>And doth not the Apoſtle call Strife, Wrath, Sedition and Hereſie the Works of the Fleſh, with Envyings, Murders and Revellings; <hi>and they that do ſuch things ſhould not inherit the Kingdom of God?</hi> Galat. 5.</p>
            <p>And have not theſe Fruits of Error, and Hereſie, and Sedition, and Diviſion you ſpeak of, been found in you, with your Wrath, Strife, Envy, Murders and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vilings, which is a Work of your Fleſh, and not a Work of the Spirit of God? as witneſs your envious Revi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling and Murdering of the Servants of God, whom you <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>nged.</p>
            <pb n="12" facs="tcp:104394:7"/>
            <p>For when it was asked <hi>Broadſtreet,</hi> one of your <hi>New-England</hi> Rulers, <hi>By what Law he Hanged the King's Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects and Servants of Chriſt?</hi> He ſaid, <hi>By the Law that they put</hi> Jeſuits <hi>to Death in</hi> England. And farther, he was asked, <hi>Whether he did believe they were</hi> Jeſuits? And he anſwered, <hi>Nay.</hi> And he was asked, <hi>Whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther he had a Hand in Hanging them?</hi> He ſaid, <hi>Yes:</hi> and from that time we could not get a ſight of him, but like a Wild Beaſt that had worryed the Doves and Lambs of Chriſt, hid himſelf in his Burrows.</p>
            <p>And are not you them that ſeduce people with vour fleſhly Minds, and preach Peace to the Birth of Fleſh, to which there is no Peace, and not to the Birth of Spirit, but war againſt it; and one builds a Wall, and another daubs it with Untempored Mortar; but when the Storm, and the Over-flowing Shour, and the Hail<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtones of God's Fury ſhall fall upon your Wall, it will deſtroy it, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 13. where you may read and ſee how he marks you out.</p>
            <p>And as <hi>Solomon</hi> ſaith, <hi>The Righteous is more excellent than his Neighbour; but the Way of the Wicked ſeduces them,</hi> Prov. 12.26. Examine your ſelves, if you be not in that Way.</p>
            <p>And did not the <hi>Heathen</hi> look upon <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> and the <hi>Jews</hi> to be a City and a People of Sedition? <hi>Ezra</hi> 4.</p>
            <p>And ſo was not God's People alwayes branded with ſuch Calumnies, and perſecuted, as you have done in <hi>New-England,</hi> by the Birth of the Fleſh, that perſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutes them that are born of the Spirit.</p>
            <p>And did not <hi>Paul</hi> confeſs to <hi>Felix,</hi> when <hi>Ananias</hi> the High Prieſt and the <hi>Jews</hi> accuſed him, <hi>That after the Way which they</hi> (to wit, the High Prieſts and El<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders,
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:104394:7"/>and profeſſing <hi>Jews) called Hereſie, ſo did he wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip the God of his Fathers, believing all things that are written in the Law and the Prophets, &amp;c. and herein did he exerciſe himſelf alwayes, to have a good Conſcience, void of Offence both towards God and towards Men,</hi> Acts 24.</p>
            <p>And ſo can the People of God called <hi>Quakers</hi> ſay now concerning the Perſecuting Prieſts and Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours of <hi>New-England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And in 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2. there you may read of the Damna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Hereſies of the Covetous Falſe Teachers, <hi>who with feigned words made Merchandize of people, which denyed the Lord that bought them, which went in the Error of</hi> Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laam, <hi>who loved the Wages of Unrighteouſneſs.</hi> And was not <hi>Balaam</hi> hired to propheſie againſt <hi>Iſrael,</hi> and to Curſe them? And are not all your Prieſts hired? Read <hi>Numb.</hi> 13. &amp; <hi>Deut.</hi> 23.</p>
            <p>And ſo have not your Teachers turned from the Command of Chriſt? who ſaith, <hi>Freely you have re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, freely give.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And do not you deny the Lord that has bought you in your Lives and Practices, though you confeſs him in words? Chriſt, <hi>who hath given himſelf a Ranſom for all, and taſted Death for every man;</hi> and ſaith, <hi>He came not to deſtroy mens Lives, but to ſave them:</hi> But you de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy the Lives of them that Chriſt dyed for: Here do not you manifeſt your ſelves to be in this Hereſie, and pernicious Wayes? And are not your Teachers ſuch as covet after Money, and have erred from the Faith, &amp;c. which Faith the Apoſtles were in, which coveted no man's Silver, nor Gold nor Apparel? And are not you all erred from this True Chriſtian, Catho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Faith, who have made Laws to Baniſh, Hang and
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:104394:8"/>Whip, Spoil Goods, and take away the People of Gods Meeting-places to make Merchandize of their Houſes and Lands, and High-wayes to them?</p>
            <p>And the Apoſtle ſaith, <hi>A man that is an Heretick after the firſt and ſecond Admonition reject.</hi> Here the Apoſtle doth not ſay, Whip him, and Baniſh him, and Hang him, and pluck down their Meeting-Houſes, and ſell them, and their Land and Wayes, though he was an Heretick: But ſuch you have not proved us, the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of God called <hi>Quakers</hi> to be; but have made a great Noiſe (like a great hollow Cask that will hold no Water) about <hi>Error</hi> and <hi>Hereſie, Schiſm</hi> and <hi>Sedition;</hi> but have not defined what any of theſe things are, nor wherein they are guilty of theſe things, whoſe Meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing-Houſes you make Laws to forfeit, pluck down, ſell and demoliſh, with the Land and High-wayes to them belonging.</p>
            <p>And you may alſo read your Error in 2 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2.17, 18, 19. and in <hi>Jude</hi> 11. ſuch as went under the Name of <hi>Chriſtians,</hi> like you, but out of the Faith and Love of God: For is not your way <hi>Cain</hi>'s, who kill about Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion? and in <hi>Corah</hi>'s, that gainſay it? Now where did ever <hi>Abraham, Iſaac</hi> and <hi>Jacob</hi> kill any becauſe they would not be of their Religion, and pluck down their Meeting Houſes, and make them forfeited, and ſell them, and the Ground and High-wayes to them?</p>
            <p>And where did ever Chriſt (who is King of Kings and Lord of Lords, who ſent his Diſciples into all Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions to preach the Goſpel to every Creature under Heaven) give any command to his Apoſtles and Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſciples, <hi>that them that would not receive their Goſpel ſome of them they ſhould Hang, &amp; others they ſhould cut off their Ears,
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:104394:8"/>&amp; others they ſhould Whip &amp; Impriſon, and ſpoil their Goods, and brand them with an Hot Iron, and ſome they ſhould Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh upon pain of Death pluck down their Meeting-Houſes, &amp; make them forfeited &amp; ſell &amp; demoliſh them, &amp; the Land &amp; High ways to them?</hi> Now ſhew us a Law from Chriſt and his Apoſtles for this your practice; or elſe acknowledge your ſelves to be no <hi>Chriſtians:</hi> And the Scriptures of the New Teſtament are not your Rule, neither have you an Example for this your Practice in all the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures of Truth. And will not ye for a piece of Bread tranſgreſs the Command of Chriſt, who ſaith, <hi>Freely you have received, freely give?</hi> Prov. 28.21. And do not your Teachers eat the Bread of Idleneſs? But the Apoſtle ſaith, <hi>They that will not work, ſhall not eat.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And do not you Workers of Iniquity go about to eat up God's People as you eat Bread, and devour them? as <hi>David</hi> ſaith, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 14. &amp; <hi>Pſal.</hi> 53. And have not you Gnaſhed upon them with your Teeth? And do not you think but the Lord will break the Long Teeth of the Ungodly, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 58. &amp; <hi>Pſal.</hi> 35. And have not your Teeth been like Spears and Arrows? <hi>Pſal.</hi> 57. But ſee what Chriſt ſaith in <hi>Mat.</hi> 13. how <hi>in the end the Wicked ſhall wail and gnaſh their Teeth, who in their Life<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time have gnaſhed them againſt God's People, and haled them before their Judgment-ſeats,</hi> as Chriſt fore-told his Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſciples. And have you not condemned and killed the Juſt, which have not reſiſted you, and baled and drawn them before your Judgment-ſeats? as in <hi>Jam.</hi> 5. And did not <hi>James</hi> pronounce Wo againſt ſuch? And have not you lifted up the Fiſts of Wickedneſs, &amp; ſmote them with it? And doth not <hi>Iſaiah</hi> teſtifie againſt ſuch Fiſts and Faſters? <hi>Iſa.</hi> 48. And doth not the Apoſtle
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:104394:9"/>exhort the <hi>Chriſtians</hi> to <hi>pray, and lift up holy hands with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Wrath and Doubting?</hi> 1 Tim. 2. And are not you Breakers of this Command with your unholy hands and fiſts of wickedneſs? who in your Wrath have Hang<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and Whipped, and now would make Forfeiture, pluck down, ſell and demoliſh the Meeting-Houſes of the People of God, with their Land and Ways to them? And doth not <hi>John</hi> ſay in the <hi>Revelations, The Beaſt with his Horns was like a Leopard:</hi> and don't you know the Nature of that ſpotted Beaſt? <hi>And his Feet were like a Bear:</hi> and hath not your Bears Paw, with your Claws been felt and ſeen? the Marks are ſeen on the Backs of the Righteous. And hath not this Beaſt a Mouth like a Lyon to devour? and the Dragon the Deſtroyer gives unto this Beaſt his <hi>deſtroying power,</hi> and the <hi>Dragons Seat</hi> and <hi>great Authority,</hi> which is to deſtroy, and not to ſave. And hath not he given you in <hi>New-England</hi> this Seat and Authority to deſtroy the Lambs of Chriſt, and to make war againſt him and his Followers? but the Lamb will overcome, <hi>Rev.</hi> 13, &amp; 17. And your Faith is not the true ſaving Faith that works by Love, but a deſtroying: nor your Goſpel is not the true Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpel of Peace and Glad-tidings, who deſtroy mens Lives, but a deſtroying one: and your Religion is not the true Religion, which is, <hi>to viſit the Fatherleſs and Widows, &amp;c.</hi> who deſtroy mens Lives, and make Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therleſs and Widows: and your Church is not the true Church, but the Whore, who drinks the Saints Blood, which the true Church of Chriſt never did: and your Worſhip is not the true Worſhip of God, in his holy Spirit and Truth, but from the foul unclean ſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit, that is out of Truth, which deſtroyes men in their
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:104394:9"/>Eſtates and Lives, and not ſave them: and your Way is not the true and living Way, Chriſt Jeſus, who ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver hanged nor ſpoiled the Goods of any that could not follow him, as you have done to ſuch as could not follow you: and your Foundation is not the true Foundation, who have hang'd, and branded, and whipt, and ſpoiled the Goods of them that would not build upon it, which Chriſt and his Apoſtles never did, though he was a Lamb ſlain from the Foundation of the World, and at laſt crucified by your Generation.</p>
            <p>And what a dreadful Fear are you in of your Falſe Religion, and Faith, and Way, and Worſhip? for what Fines have you laid on Maſters of Ships that bring over the Servants of the Lord, and Fines upon them that do receive them, and Fines on them that do bring or receive a Book, as your Laws declare! Oh, what a pitiful, fearful, evil Spirit you are of! And the Apoſtle ſaith, <hi>Quench not the Spirit:</hi> and why ſhould you quench the Spirit in any? And he ſaith, <hi>Deſpiſe not Prophecy:</hi> &amp; is not this deſpiſing of Prophecy, who will not ſuffer ſuch to come among you to propheſie? And how far from the Apoſtles Doctrine are you, who ſaith, <hi>Prove all things, and hold faſt that which is goode</hi> 1 <hi>Theſ.</hi> 5. And the Apoſtle <hi>John</hi> ſaith, <hi>Theſe things have I writen unto you, concerning them that ſeduce you; but the Anointing that you have received of him, abideth in you, and you need not that any man teach you, but as the ſame Anoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing teacheth you of all things, and is Truth, and is no Lye; and even as it hath taught you, ye ſhall abide in him.</hi> Now are not the <hi>New-England Governours, Prieſts</hi> and <hi>Elders</hi> theſe <hi>Seducers,</hi> that <hi>hang, baniſh, whip, priſon, brand with an hot Iron, ſpoil their Goods, make their Meeting-houſes forfeited, and ſell and demoliſh their Houſes and Lands and
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:104394:10"/>Wayes to them, of ſuch as cannot forſake the Anointings Teachings within,</hi> according to the Apoſtle's Doctrine, which Teachings of the <hi>Anointing</hi> within brings them to continue in the Son of God, &amp; in the Father, which <hi>Anointing</hi> they cannot forſake, to follow the ſeducing ſpirit of you and your perſecuting Prieſts, who have <hi>hanged</hi> ſome, and <hi>branded</hi> ſome, and <hi>baniſhed</hi> others, and <hi>whipt</hi> and <hi>ſpoiled their Goods;</hi> and now made a Law, <hi>to forfeit their Meeting-Houſes, and Lands &amp; wayes to them.</hi> But <hi>all theſe things cannot ſeparate them from the Love of God, which they have in Chriſt Jeſus.</hi> And as the Saints have formerly ſaid, <hi>Who ſhall ſeparate us from the Love of Chriſt? ſhall Tribulation, Diſtreſs, Perſecution, Famin, Nakedneſs, Peril or Sword?</hi> as it is written, <hi>For Chriſt's ſake we are killed all the day long; we are counted as Sheep for the Slaughter:</hi> and you Slaughterers, who have your Slaughtering-place to ſlaughter and hang God's People in. <hi>But in all theſe things we are more than Conque<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rors through Chriſt who hath loved us. And the Devil and his Angels, with all his Principallities and dark Powers, are not able to ſeparate and ſeduce God's People from Chriſt, and the Unction which they have from him, by which they come to continue in the Son of God, and in the Father, through which they feel the Love of God, by which they are kept above the fear of man, and what he can do unto them, which Love bears and endures all things, and envyes not.</hi> So bleſſed be God through Chriſt for this Love, who hath ſhed it abroad in his Peoples Hearts.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>And the Lord forgive you all your Perſecution of his Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, and that you may Repent, if it be his Will, who deſires not your Deſtruction, but your Salvation.</hi> G. F.</signed>
               <dateline>
                  <date>The 19th of the 7th Moneth, 1679.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="postscript">
            <pb n="19" facs="tcp:104394:10"/>
            <head>Poſtſcript.</head>
            <p>AND whereas <hi>Joſeph Shaddeck</hi> writes to <hi>William Croutch</hi> a Letter, dated the 30th of the 4th moneth, 1679. <hi>That one</hi> John Higginſon <hi>preach't at</hi> Salem <hi>the</hi> 29th <hi>of the</hi> 4th <hi>mon.</hi> 79. <hi>and in his Sermon ſaid, That</hi> Fox, <hi>and</hi> Penn, <hi>and ſeveral others of the</hi> Quakers, <hi>were now found out to be</hi> Jeſuits, <hi>and had a great hand in carrying on the Plot in</hi> England; <hi>and that the Wandering</hi> Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers <hi>were the Cauſe of ſtirring up the laſt bloody Wars by the</hi> Indians <hi>in theſe parts.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But theſe are all invented and forged Lyes, as it is well known in <hi>England,</hi> that are caſt upon <hi>Fox</hi> and <hi>Penn;</hi> but <hi>Fox</hi> and <hi>Penn</hi> abhor their Slanders, and the forged Lyes which the ſaid <hi>John Higginſon</hi> preach't at <hi>Salem</hi> for Goſpel: It is like he wanted ſomething to make up his Hour-Glaſs. And thoſe are alſo forged Lyes from a ſlanderous Mouth and Tongue, to ſay, <hi>That the Wandring</hi> Quakers <hi>were the Cauſe of ſtirring up the bloody Wars by the</hi> Indians <hi>in</hi> New-England. Nay, theſe are the Wandring Stars, that forge theſe Lyes, and caſt up their Mire and Dirt againſt the Innocent: For the very Records of the beginning of thoſe Wars give the <hi>New-England</hi> Prieſts, with the Raiſers of the Forgeries before, thoſe Wandring Stars, the Lye; and that they are For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers of Lyes againſt the Innocent People of God called <hi>Quakers:</hi> For their very Innocent Principle, and the Nature of their true <hi>Chriſtianity,</hi> who are Partakers of the Divine Nature of Chriſt, doth abhor and deny ſuch Practices and Plots of the <hi>Jeſuits,</hi> of ſtirring up Bloodſhed and Wars. For, our Lord Jeſus Chriſt <hi>came not to Deſtroy mens Lives, but to Save them.</hi> So it is contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry to the Nature of Jeſus Chriſt our Lord, and contrary to the Nature of the true <hi>Chriſtians,</hi> that receive him, as <hi>Fox</hi> and <hi>Penn</hi> do; and ſuch receive him whom the Prieſts of <hi>New-England</hi> call
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:104394:11"/>
               <hi>[Wandring Quakers]</hi> with their ſlanderous Tongues and For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers of Lyes, who make Lyes their Refuge, and are the Preach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of Lyes to the People inſtead of the Goſpel; &amp; we do believe, that the <hi>Magiſtrates, Prieſts</hi> and <hi>Agents</hi> of <hi>New-England</hi> would have had it ſo; and therefore endeavouring to make people believe Lyes, that they might be damned; and this is to ſtir up Wars: and it is the Devil's Wo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>k in them, who is their Father, and a Lyar from the beginning, to ſtir them up to Lyes, Envy, Malice, Wrath and Evil-ſpeaking againſt the Innocent. And therefore, as <hi>Paul</hi> ſaith to <hi>Timothy, Such Evil Men and Seducers as you ſhall wax worſe and worſe, deceiving and being deceived, whoſe latter-end is worſe than your beginning; which are Wells without Water, and Clouds carryed about with Tempeſts, though you may ſpeak great ſwelling words of Vanity; to whom is reſerved the miſt of Darkneſs and Blackneſs forever.</hi> But the Proverb is upon you, <hi>The Dog</hi> (the Biter) <hi>is turned again to his Vomit, and the Sow to the wal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing in the Mire;</hi> who throw your ſtinking Vomit and ſilthy Mire upon the Innocent People of God in ſcorn called <hi>Quakers:</hi> So you have eaten of the Fruit of Lyes, and are compaſſed about with them, as you may ſee in <hi>Hoſea</hi> 10, &amp; 11. <hi>And a Falſe Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs wi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>l utter Lyes; a Deceitful Witneſs ſpeaks Lyes,</hi> as you may ſee in <hi>Proverbs.</hi> And have you not bent your Tongues like Bows to utter Lyes, and taught your Tongues to ſpeak Lyes? <hi>Jer.</hi> 9. And have you not cauſed the people to err by your Lyes? <hi>Jer.</hi> 23. <hi>And a Lying Tongue is but for a moment; and Lying Lips are an Abomination to the Lord,</hi> Prov. 12. And ſo have not you like <hi>Ahab,</hi> ſold your ſelves to work wickedneſs, as in 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 21.20. in your Lying, and Slandering, and Perſecuting the Servants of the Lord? and what you cannot do with your Hands, you do it with your Tongues.</p>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
